What do we do in this course: we design
rational agents. What's that?
An agent is some entity that perceives
and acts.
What does that mean, well here's an agent,
an agent that's trying to get at some kind
of apple. We'll come back to
this agent again later.
We can think about this agent with the
following diagram--we'll draw these
agent diagrams from time to time.
There's an environment and there's an agent.
What's the difference? The
environment is what you don't control,
the agent is what you do.
So, in particular, where you draw that
boundary--you might think when
you're driving the agent is like the car, it can turn left and it can turn right. But the agent
is also your arms. You have to move
the steering wheel.
If the car is not working right maybe you want to think of the car as the environment, or
maybe your arms not working right--you
threw out your elbow driving so hard.
Now the line between the agent and the
environment is in your head. You can send
the signal to your arm but who knows
what your trick arm is going to do.
And so where we draw this abstraction,
just like everything else in computer science,
depends on the problem we're solving
and what abstraction is safe.
Okay, so what can an agent do?
It can perceive,
we have percepts coming in.
We have actions going to the
environment. What does the environment do?
It does whatever the environment does.
The world does its thing.
And then the agent
takes what comes in and it formulates an action
using the question mark.
What the heck is the question mark?
That's the all important agent function.
That's the thing that maps inputs (sensation)
to outputs (actuation).
So a rational agent chooses actions that
maximizes its utilities. Since it doesn't
know what's gonna happen, like this agent's
not really sure whether it's going to succeed,
we have to talk about
expectations. The characteristics of the
percepts, the environment, the action
space tell us how to solve the problem.
If an agent can see everything, that's
one thing. If the agent can't, that's another thing.
So, for example, if you think about a video game.
Sometimes you can see the whole board,
sometimes there's the fog-of-war, and in
general, you don't always have full information.
The techniques you use are different.
This class is largely about general AI
techniques
that apply to a variety of problems
types,
and about learning to recognize when and
how a problem
can be solved by one of those techniques,
by thinking about what kinds of
percepts do I have, what kinds of environment do I have. Is it adversarial,
is it fully observed,
and so on. And as we go through this course
you'll get more and more of these tools
to deal with more and more complicated environments.